Volodymyr Bilokur



Berlin, Germany

Tel: +49 152 169 45598 E-mail: vladimino@gmail.com

Personal data

Date of birth: 31.03.1982 Citizenship: Ukraine Marital status: Married

Work permission: Blue Card owner

Engineering Leader at your service

Summary

I am building and growing high-performant teams for a decade already. The strong technical background helps me to understand what my team members say and advise them. An ability to be present and listen carefully allows me to discover how my team members feel and support them. Learnings from the broad experience give me an opportunity to direct my team members towards their growth and coach them. And finally, an infectious inspiration I cultivate by connecting my team members to the vision engages them to achieve the goals and keeps our customers satisfied. Sounds like someone you're looking for? Let's get in touch.

Work experience

Backend Lead Developer at Campanda

July 2019 (1 month)

(https://www.campanda.com/)

I joined Campanda as Backend Lead and together with the new VP of Engineering we were building ambitious plans to migrate project into mature e-commerce system and grow the team. Platform has been chosen and the team started to work on modeling RV marketplace there but lack of investments forced executives to a very radical decision: massive lay offs and salary drop for the ones who stay.

Senior PHP Developer at Holiday Pirates

February 2019 – June 2019 (5 months)

(https://www.holidaypirates.com/)

I started as a senior developer in order to solve challenging tasks and grow within flat hierarchy to become a lead. Unfortunately, it turned out that tasks are more trivial and there are not so many opportunities to grow.

Engineering Manager at Wayfair

October 2016 – November 2018 (2 years 1 month)

(http://www.wayfair.de/)

I was managing the cross-functional team of 7 in Merchandising Engineering. One of the key achievements of my team is fully automated critical product addition process which decreased turnaround time by 45%.

Key Responsibilities:

- Understanding of big picture, setting context and focus
- Project planning, dependency and risk management, result delivery
- Building, support and development of the team
- Hiring and mentoring

Senior Software Engineer at Wayfair

(http://www.wayfair.de/)

Before promotion I was working as an individual contributor within Product Catalog team. I was developing in PHP 7 with a focus on code quality, maintained legacy MS SQL business logic (in stored procedures, triggers and functions) and became a certified code reviewer. I had whole ownership of a couple of big projects that significantly improved life for our main stakeholders (Merchandising team).

Senior Backend Developer at HelloFresh

August 2015 – February 2016 (6 months)

(http://hellofresh.de)

During these 6 months at HelloFresh I've been part of 3 different teams and made impact on different areas of the project (operations, SCM, CRM). Key responsibilities were PHP development (including API integration) with DevOps mentalty (*you build it, you run it*). I designed and developed a couple of important microservices.

CTO at EasyFinance (https://easyfinance.ru/)

June 2014 – July 2015 (1 year)

EasyFinance is a leading Personal Finance Management Service in Russia. My duties there, along with team leading and developing most critical modules, included the responsibility to make final technical decisions, communication with partners, developing a project plan, measuring a productivity and growing the team.

Engineering Director at 3A Interactive

July 2012 – May 2014 (1 year 11 months)

(http://bottle-game.com)

Team Leader at PlayFast Technologies

March 2010 - June 2012 (2 years 4 months)

IT Director at Moskva.com

September 2009 - December 2009 (4 months)

Lead Developer at Strana Online

September 2009 - January 2010 (5 months)

Lead Developer at Electronic World of Ukraine

March 2008 - August 2009 (1 year 6 months)

Web Developer at Kore Design Studios Inc.

November 2005 - September 2007 (1 year 11 months)

Developer, Product Manager at National Multimedia Company

August 2003 - October 2006 (3 years 3 months)

Education

The National Technical University of Ukraine "Kyiv Polytechnic Institute"

Degree: Bachelor of Computer Science, 2003

Specialty: Computer Programming of Automated Systems

Volunteer Experience

- Mentor at Coding Coach (https://mentors.codingcoach.io/?language=ru)
- Mentor for PHP Track at **Exercism** (https://exercism.io/tracks/php/mentors)

Language Skills

English: Fluent German: Basic

<u>Ukrainian</u>: Bilingual proficiency <u>Russian</u>: Bilingual proficiency